We are in TigJam Winnipeg. We are here with like 20, 30 other game developers.
TigJam is the independent game jam. It's kind of formed out of the TigSource online community.
Everybody's making amazing things.
Basically everyone just brings a laptop, works on whatever they feel like working on,
whether it's like a new project or something they've been working on for a long time.
You push all that other stuff out and for two days you work really, really hard to usually make a new thing
that somehow you either needed an excuse to make or you had no idea you were going to make in the first place,
but it sort of captured your imagination.
At the jam, my jam game started out as like four different games.
Today I've been working on a thing that has no name yet.
I coded this like circular room.
You are a guy with a jet pack.
Okay, the guy will have like a sword thing.
And you fly around.
You'll be able to swing this sword thing around.
And shoot things.
And it gets thinner as it's longer, that kind of thing.
And then you can land and dash at stuff.
It evolved into this cool project with suggestions from all these different people
where I'm actually trying out a cool mechanic and trying out a cool intuitive way of moving,
that kind of thing.
It's a lot of different things that haven't quite come together yet.
I made a little skier game.
I want to make a game that's like a ragdoll track and field kind of game.
So you're kind of this little skier ragdoll puppet guy.
And if you move the mouse up, he moves up.
If you move the mouse down, he moves down.
And then you can kind of move the mouse around to control him.
And it flips and move up.
So I started this yesterday.
It's reasonably playable for what it is.
So rather than mash buttons really hard and really fast to do stuff,
you kind of puppeteer these little ragdoll characters.
There's this game called QWOP that did this.
But QWOP made something easy really difficult.
And I want to make things that are difficult really easy.
Like it's really hard to go skiing and do a double front flip.
But it's pretty easy to do it in a game.
And that's kind of where the fun is.
So I think that's the better approach.
I wanted to prototype some ideas for that.
You learn a ton just by hanging out in this kind of environment
because people are just viewing useful information about game making all the time.
Well, you get this sort of exchange of ideas that you don't necessarily...
It's a lot more raw in your person than just reading things on forums.
It changes how you develop games.
It turns them into this social thing,
this thing where you share your ideas openly with people.
I think it's supposed to remind us that, yeah, you can do whatever you want for two days.
Like that's the goal of it is just to do whatever you want
as opposed to, oh, I have to get this next feature set for this next milestone,
for this next funding payment or whatever it is.
I know it's a great opportunity to bring everybody together
because we're all spread out all over the world.
It's great to be in the same place and meet up with everybody again.
It's amazing to be in a room with people doing wonderful things.
www.mooji.org