Yeah.
One of the main things about how I operate my business is that I believe games are art.
Some people say that games can't be art because they believe that they are simply a lower
form of entertainment.
My belief is that they can't not be art.
It's really impossible for it not to be art.
Hi, I'm Alec Kaloka from Infinite Ammo Incorporated, and I make games.
I have a kind of weird family.
We all kind of do creative stuff together, so as a kid, like, my dad would get us to
make board games together.
We'd actually draw the boards, we'd draw the cards, we'd make up the rules, and my dad
was actually a big influence in getting me into game programming because he bought me
a book called Basic Fun when I was eight years old and invited one of my cousins over to
help teach me if statements, which are one of the fundamental aspects of programming,
basically.
If one thing is happening, do this.
Else, do something else.
And we made this little maze game together where you walk through a maze with little
animations just done with text characters.
And so that was sort of the first time I actually had made anything.
The real cool thing about games is that it's like a fusion of visual stuff, audio stuff,
interactive stuff like board games and rule sets all into one.
And so what I'm really interested in is how do all those things work together to create
a cohesive experience.
So the projects that I have been involved with and am involved with include Aquaria,
Paper Moon, Heroes and Villains for the iPhone, Marion, hopefully for the Xbox.
Aquaria was a game that I released in 2007.
It was created by myself and my friend Derek Yu, who is from San Francisco.
Basically it was me sort of working by myself and interacting with Derek on the internet.
So a lot of the experience of developing this by myself and being alone in an apartment
kind of worked its way into the story of the game.
So the main character of the game is Nyjah, who is a character who is totally alone in
this really beautiful underwater world and has to find out who she is and what her purpose
is.
The game went on to win the Seamus McNally Grand Prize Award at the Independent Games
Festival, which was like a huge moment.
It was really interesting because my dad was actually there.
He flew down from Winnipeg to go to San Francisco to see these awards.
He was the one who got me into games as a kid.
There was always this tension between us of sort of like, you know, you always have to
prove to your father that you can do something.
I remember it came down to the part where the team that won last year came out and started
to introduce the award.
I remember thinking to myself, this is like a Back to the Future 2 moment where Doc Brown
is saying that the timelines are going to diverge in two different directions.
If we win the award, it's going to be a completely different thing than if we don't.
So fortunately, we won.
It was a brain-shattering moment because I almost couldn't process it.
What?
Being an independent game developer requires a ton of different skills because you don't
have a boatload of money that you can just throw at people to do stuff for you.
So one of the things that Infinite Ammo does to survive and operate as a company in the
indie game space is collaborate with a lot of different people who are all over the place.
I'm collaborating on a number of iPhone game projects, one's with a guy in Chicago, one's
with a guy called Phil Fish in Montreal.
I'm looking at doing another one with a guy from Britain.
So really it's this community that spans the globe.
It's this really close, trusted network of creative individuals who work together to
create unique stuff.
Yes!
Winnipeg's kind of the butt of a lot of jokes, and that's fine because indie game developers
are always kind of the underdog, and Winnipeg's kind of like a perpetual underdog.
So I think it's a good match.
I grew up here, I spent most of my life here, and lots of elements of the city are ingrained
in my mind in both real and imaginary ways, like the ways I saw them as a kid.
So this sense of old architecture, this sense of strange toys, all kinds of things that
have influenced me to want to explore certain things in the games that I make.
I would like Infinite Ammo to be known for both games that are fun to pick up and play
and just enjoy, and also games that are really deep that you can dive into and get lost in.
And they're both completely different things.
So it's kind of an interesting point because I'm developing a number of games that are
short and fun and easy to pick up and play, and I'm developing this other game that's
this huge, sprawling epic that hopefully people will be able to lose themselves in.
I'd like to be able to do both, whether that's possible or not is another question.